# Teun Zengerink

Senior Software Engineer

# Personal details

Location: Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Email address: <u>teun@cyberpeaks.nl</u> Phone number: +31 6 5471 6572

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tzengerink/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/tzengerink/</a>

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/tzengerink/">https://github.com/tzengerink/</a>
Company: <a href="https://www.cyberpeaks.nl/">https://www.cyberpeaks.nl/</a>
Personal: <a href="https://teun.zengerink.com/">https://teun.zengerink.com/</a>



Software engineer with over 13 years of professional experience. Passionate about developing creative solutions that have an impact on its users and society. Motivated to guide organizations in implementing Agile/Scrum practices, mentor junior developers and improve engineering processes. Admired by peers for being reliable, critical, authentic, outspoken, opinionated and emphatic.

# Developer Experience

#### Languages & Frameworks

TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Angular, Vue.js, Next.js, Redux, RxJS, GraphQL, Material UI, Tailwind, Sass, Less, Jest, Playwright, Cypress, Node.js, Yarn, Vite, Webpack

Tools & Platforms	Design & Project Management
GitHub, GitLab, Azure DevOps, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Amazon Web Service, Microsoft Azure, Cloudflare	Scrum, Jira, Confluence, Trello, Figma, Adobe Photoshop





# Work Experience

#### Senior Fullstack Developer

Nationale Nederlanden, September 2023 - February 2024

Migrate a customer facing portal application to a new technology stack.

- Setup of new technology stack and collaborate with UI/UX-designer to create an optimal end user experience for the portal application.
- Create a backend for the frontend to communicate with SAP data storage through a configurable API gateway.
- Tech used: TypeScript, React, Next.js, Material UI, Node.js, NPM, Vite, Azure DevOps, Gitlab, Figma, Scrum

#### Senior Frontend Developer

MyWheels, March 2022 - July 2023

Creating new frontend functionalities for mobile app, website and back-office application.

- Introduce automated testing and stricter TypeScript compiler options to increase code quality, maintainability and reliability.
- Assist growing development team in introducing the Scrum philosophy to add more predictability in creation of valuable output.
- Tech used: TypeScript, React, React-Native, Next.js, Jest, GraphQL,
   Yarn, Webpack, Tailwind, GitLab, Jenkins, Jira, Figma, Scrum

### Senior Frontend Developer

Rabobank (via Accenture), Augustus 2021 - February 2022

Developing user interfaces for the onboarding flows that provide a fluent experience for new customers in opening a bank account.

- Improve state management by introducing Redux to produce consistent application behavior, while also reducing code duplication.
- Implement stricter TypeScript compiler options to create stronger quarantees of program correctness and easier code collaboration.
- Tech used: TypeScript, Angular, Redux, RxJS, Sass, Yarn, Jest, Azure DevOps, Microsoft Azure, Jira, Scrum

#### Senior Frontend Developer

GrandVision (via Cygni), January 2021 - July 2021 Building a whitelabel frontend for use in a MACH architecture serving eCommerce sites for multiple operating companies (Pearl, EyeWish, VisionExpress and others).

- Coordinate with Product Owner and Business Analyst to validate requirements and define technical approach for its implementation.
- Mentor and assist (junior) frontend developers in the team.
- Tech used: TypeScript, React, Redux, Sass, GraphQL, Jest, Yarn,
   Next.js, Lerna, Webpack, GitHub, Microsoft Azure, Jira, Scrum

#### Photography Internship

Takeaway.com, February 2020 - July 2020



#### Product Owner

Usabilla, August 2018 - December 2019

Accountable for iOS and Android SDK as well as the React-Native, Cordova and Xamarin bridges for those SDKs.

- Revamped the user interface of the forms while thoroughly testing it to meet accessibility standards.
- Improved the flow for enriching feedback items by attaching screenshots and camera images.
- Made use of design sprints, customer journey maps, problem area definitions, personas, brainstorms and validation interviews.

#### Senior Fullstack Software Engineer

Usabilla, January 2016 - August 2018

Responsible for creating well architected and maintainable code that meets the described requirements and end user expectations.

- Collaborated closely with the Product Owner, UX/UI designers and other engineers.
- Mentored junior engineers and participated in discussions with designers to create the best overall experience.
- Tech used: TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Angular, Jest, Sass, Node.js, PHP, Python, Symfony, D3.js, AWS, Jira, Scrum

#### Fullstack Developer

TROI Studio, December 2010 - January 2016

Tech used: JavaScript, Angular, Less, Python, PHP, Flask, MySQL, AWS, Linux, Docker

#### Fullstack Developer

Studenten.net, January 2010 - December 2010

Tech used: JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, .NET

## Education

Bachelor Arts, Culture and Media

Rijksuniversiteit Groningen, September 2006 - June 2009

Bachelor Business Administration and Computer Science Hanzehogeschool Groningen, September 2002 - June 2006

## Certification

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer

Cloud Native Computing Foundation, August 2021

Certified Scrum Master

Xebia, January 2017

